<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>angr</title><link>http://zacanger.com/blog</link>
<description>writings from zac anger, who is not all that angry</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:06:11 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:06:11 -0600</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://zacanger.com/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
NOTES FROM DEVMOUNTAIN
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is going to be a crapton of my notes, from when I was going through the course at DevMountain.</p>

<p>Looking back over these, a lot of them are dumb. What I mean by this is that my opinions on things were dumb.</p>

<p>Whatever.</p>

<p>Don't take it all so seriously. Some of it could be really helpful. This is about half of my collected
notes <em>that were inside project files</em>. Everything else has already been cleaned up and posted, or is in
a directory of drafts somewhere. This stuff is totally unedited.</p>

<hr />
<p>tags: <a href='tag_notes.html'>notes</a>, <a href='tag_devmountain.html'>devmountain</a>, <a href='tag_lol.html'>lol</a>, <a href='tag_i-am-ridiculous.html'>i-am-ridiculous</a>, <a href='tag_directives.html'>directives</a>, <a href='tag_angular.html'>angular</a>, <a href='tag_firebase.html'>firebase</a>, <a href='tag_express.html'>express</a>, <a href='tag_mongo.html'>mongo</a>, <a href='tag_mongoose.html'>mongoose</a>, <a href='tag_node.html'>node</a>, <a href='tag_ionic.html'>ionic</a>, <a href='tag_d3.html'>d3</a>, <a href='tag_react.html'>react</a>, <a href='tag_heroku.html'>heroku</a>, <a href='tag_digital-ocean.html'>digital-ocean</a></p>
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/notes-from-devmountain.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='https://twitter.com/search?q=http://zacanger.com/blog/notes-from-devmountain.html'><span id='count-18760'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/notes-from-devmountain.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./notes-from-devmountain.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:00:00 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Thanksgiving Week, Projects, Fun Times, and The Future
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Jesus fuck it's been an interesting week. I've learned so much this week, and managed to get almost nothing done. <a href="http://npm.im/markvi">Markvi</a> is up to version 0.3.0, because it now actually has the keybinds it was always meant to have. The tentatively titled <em>Whiteboard</em> is stuck in planning, because I kind of stopped caring about it, though I really need to get that one done since it's the main project that actually matters, here. The other project (the thing that has to do with documentation, and making money) is stalled, but I'm so ready to get moving on that because it's super exciting.</p>

<hr />
<p>tags: <a href='tag_school.html'>school</a>, <a href='tag_personal.html'>personal</a>, <a href='tag_wiki.html'>wiki</a>, <a href='tag_projects.html'>projects</a>, <a href='tag_vue.html'>vue</a>, <a href='tag_mithril.html'>mithril</a>, <a href='tag_js.html'>js</a></p>
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/thanksgiving-week-projects-fun-times-and-the-future.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/thanksgiving-week-projects-fun-times-and-the-future.html'><span id='count-14658'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/thanksgiving-week-projects-fun-times-and-the-future.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./thanksgiving-week-projects-fun-times-and-the-future.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
That was fast.
</title><description><![CDATA[

<h3>Just a note:</h3>

<p>I'mma go ahead and deploy this now. I'm doing things the old fashioned way (that is, FTP) because IIS is the worst and it makes me sad. I've decided to stick with bashblog for the moment, only because baker is more than I need. So is bashblog, for that matter, but baker also brings along <a href="http://getbootstrap.com">Bootstrap</a> weight, and that's really not something I can see myself needing in blog context. Mostly I write things in Markdown, sometimes peeking in on them with a nifty live preview script to check things; I don't need widgets and animations and such, here.</p>

<p>Anyhow, I'll now begin the long work of cleaning up all these old posts for self-hosting. Thank goodness.</p>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_meta.html'>meta</a>, <a href='tag_bashblog.html'>bashblog</a>, <a href='tag_blogging.html'>blogging</a></p>







<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/that-was-fast.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/that-was-fast.html'><span id='count-29368'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/that-was-fast.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./that-was-fast.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
things learned dealing with electron and the mean stack
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>In the interest of <a href="http://coffeecoder.net/blog/blog-little-things/">blogging the little things</a>, I want to write down a couple of things I learned while struggling through <a href="https://github.com/zacanger/ayuba.git">my project</a>. Nothing major, but a few things that I really had to dig to find answers to, buried way underneath unrelated issues in Github and whatnot.</p>

<hr />
<p>tags: <a href='tag_javascript.html'>javascript</a>, <a href='tag_js.html'>js</a>, <a href='tag_electron.html'>electron</a>, <a href='tag_angular.html'>angular</a>, <a href='tag_mean.html'>mean</a>, <a href='tag_school.html'>school</a>, <a href='tag_css.html'>css</a></p>
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/things-learned-dealing-with-electron-and-the-mean-stack.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/things-learned-dealing-with-electron-and-the-mean-stack.html'><span id='count-14163'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/things-learned-dealing-with-electron-and-the-mean-stack.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./things-learned-dealing-with-electron-and-the-mean-stack.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
This Here's A Test!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Well, all right! This is just a little test. I've tried what may well be five or six dozen static site/blog generators over the past few months, and I'm back at two of the ones I tried first--<a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog">Bashblog</a> and <a href="https://github.com/taylorchu/baker">Baker</a>. They're both written in bash, and both pretty simple. I dig bashblog's one-file thing, and kind of like the extreme simplicity of the post-editing format, but it's a little sloppy and requires some disassembly to actually configure. Baker's quite a bit easier to work with, and quite a bit more attractive by default, but it's also about three times the size of bashblog. Both of them seem to have Discus/disquszszs/diskust really stuck in there, and I'm not actually in the mood to sign up for yet <em>another</em> social platform, so... we'll have to see about that. OH, and neither one wants to use an alternate implementation of Markdown. not that I mind, there's nothing terribly wrong with the original one from <a href="http://daringfireball.net">John Gruber</a>, but I'd prefer to at least have that option. There are versions in C and Python that I like (and the C is obviously much faster), as well as the various Javascript implementations that are all the rage these days. It'd also be nice to work with some extensions. I'm never sure what's kosher in the original because I rarely use it, but I'm fairly certain I can't do tables and syntax hightlighting here.</p>

<p>ANYWAY. This is just a quick first post, as a test. I'll be doing the same in Baker, and then following up by (gradually) reposting all of my archived blog posts from other platforms, and saved drafts/notes in my Dropbox.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>

<p>-Z</p>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_meta.html'>meta</a>, <a href='tag_bashblog.html'>bashblog</a>, <a href='tag_markdown.html'>markdown</a>, <a href='tag_blogging.html'>blogging</a></p>






























<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/this-heres-a-test.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/this-heres-a-test.html'><span id='count-28006'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/this-heres-a-test.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./this-heres-a-test.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
tone and voice
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>How you write something is more important than what you write. What good is
having all the knowledge in the world if it cannot be shared? Having a good
tone and voice is key to becoming likeable. Companies like Slack do a
magnificent job at conveying <em>likeability</em>.</p>

<h2>Frames</h2>

<p>Tone and voice is an abstract concept; talking about it mostly hits the
superficial level, the <em>how</em> of things. Framing is more integral to the message
in that it is the actual message itself. When you convey information, there's a
certain frame attached to it. What is the goal you're trying to achieve with
the information you're sending; what is the feeling you're trying to invoke?
Framing is staple to language, and recognizing the frame someone is using can
lead to a sharper understanding of someone's message.</p>

<h2>Error messages</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/devel/static/error-style-guide.html">error style guide</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>See also</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://bufferapp.com/tone-guide">Buffer Voice / Tone Guide</a></li>
<li><a href="http://taalstrategie.nl/framing/">taalstrategie (Dutch)</a></li>
</ul>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_tone.html'>tone</a>, <a href='tag_voice.html'>voice</a>, <a href='tag_design.html'>design</a></p>






<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/tone-and-voice.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/tone-and-voice.html'><span id='count-10135'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/tone-and-voice.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./tone-and-voice.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Treatise on Minimalism
</title><description><![CDATA[

<ul>
<li>Minimalism should increase your happiness and contentment.</li>
<li>Less is powerful.</li>
<li>Elimination is incredibly powerful.</li>
<li>No one can eliminate everything.</li>
<li>Elimination without self-awareness is dangerous and harmful.</li>
<li>Fix you before you fix your stuff.</li>
<li>Minimalism is the most intense form of expression possible.</li>
<li>Your stuff has no objective value.</li>
<li>Beware of potential.</li>
<li>There are no right minimalism answers, only theory and extrapolation.</li>
<li>Minimalism is an enhancer, not a finder.</li>
<li>Upkeep is all of the battle.</li>
<li>You can't eliminate mistakes.</li>
<li>Minimalism is distilling life.</li>
<li>Focus creates beauty or abhorrence. You decide which.</li>
<li>Minimalism is respected.</li>
<li>Portability.</li>
<li>Necessity is fluid.</li>
<li>Memento mori.</li>
</ul>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_minimalism.html'>minimalism</a>, <a href='tag_manifesto.html'>manifesto</a>, <a href='tag_treatise.html'>treatise</a>, <a href='tag_design.html'>design</a></p>






<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/treatise-on-minimalism.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/treatise-on-minimalism.html'><span id='count-3024'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/treatise-on-minimalism.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./treatise-on-minimalism.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
UI
</title><description><![CDATA[

<h2>UI</h2>

<h3>Systems</h3>

<ul>
<li>Modular is good</li>
<li>Cards are good</li>
<li>Systems are good</li>
<li>Consistency is good</li>
</ul>

<h4>Future Trends:</h4>

<ul>
<li>Design systems</li>
<li>Designing for change</li>
<li>Designing personalized experiences</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="http://blog.intercom.io/design-futures-1-creating-systems-not-products/">Systems mean fast iteration means success.</a></p>

<h3>Elements</h3>

<p>Interfaces are composed of small components, which are composed of small primitives. <br />
This lowest granular level only consists of a few elements:</p>

<ul>
<li>Buttons</li>
<li>Forms</li>
<li>Lists</li>
</ul>

<p>Everything else is usually a superset of these elements.</p>

<h3>Trends</h3>

<p>Don't buy into the hype. Not everything is a good thing. A lot of things are actually <br />
really bad things, especially for the users you might not be considering.</p>

<ul>
<li>Parallax -- good for flashiness, bad for a11y, users, browsers</li>
<li>Card -- good all around, for the right application</li>
<li>Media object -- an example of the <em>elements</em> way of doings, the 'poster child of oocss'</li>
<li>Infinite scroll -- again, looks cool, but all around actually a very bad thing to do</li>
<li>Smooth scroll -- it's not necessarily harmful, but it's not exactly fantastic, either</li>
</ul>

<h3>Natural Language Form</h3>

<p>Forms that aren't just inputs. Mad-libs style, so one doesn't have a giant box of empty <br />
boxes to fill in, but instead something like
<a href="http://www.lukew.com/ff/entry.asp?1007">I want my username to be {username} and my password to be {password}</a>, or 
<a href="http://www.jroehm.com/2014/01/ui-pattern-natural-language-form/">I'm looking for {restaurant} in {city} at {time}.</a></p>

<h3>Empty States</h3>

<ul>
<li>Zero-data states</li>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/design/spec/patterns/empty-states.html">When there's no content</a></li>
<li>Should not just be an afterthought</li>
<li><a href="http://emptystat.es">Excellent Examples</a></li>
</ul>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_ui.html'>ui</a>, <a href='tag_design.html'>design</a>, <a href='tag_guidelines.html'>guidelines</a>, <a href='tag_ux.html'>ux</a>, <a href='tag_css.html'>css</a>, <a href='tag_js.html'>js</a></p>







<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/ui.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/ui.html'><span id='count-24302'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/ui.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./ui.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Unicode
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Unicode is not a 16-bit system. Unlike mapping letters to bits (<code>A =&gt; 0100 0001</code>, for example), with unicode, characters are mapped to a theoretical concept called a <strong>code point</strong>. So it's an... ideal.</p>

<p>This 'code point' ideal is represented by the numbers we've already seen, like <code>U+0639</code>, and such. The numbers are hexadecimal (base 16) (and the <code>U+</code> prefix is for 'unicode').</p>

<p>So, early on in the life of unicode, the idea was to store those numbers in two bytes each. But then there was some high-school level drama between the high-endian clique and the low-endian gang, so now we have this <code>FF FE</code> or whatever at the beginning--that's the Unicode <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byte_order_mark">BOM</a>.</p>

<p>But <em>then</em>, basically because Americans were still using the same restricted set of the Latin alphabet, we came up with UTF-8. That kind of screwed everyone else over, because now we have 0-127 all in one singe byte, and then 128 on up stored in 2-6 bytes. So the characters we use every day in American English still look the same as before (when we used ASCII), but now a whole bunch of other scripts (and symbols) are kind of screwy, because it takes several bytes to use other characters.</p>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_unicode.html'>unicode</a>, <a href='tag_text.html'>text</a>, <a href='tag_ascii.html'>ascii</a></p>







<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/unicode.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/unicode.html'><span id='count-18246'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/unicode.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./unicode.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Visual Studio Code's License
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>...is crap.</p>
<ul>
  <li>This software is a pre-release. It may not operate correctly[...]. Microsoft may change iit for the final,
    commercial version.</li>
  <li>This software will stop running on 31/12/2016. You will not receive any other notice. You will not be able to
    access data used with the software when it stops running.</li>
  <li>The softare[...](collects) data about you. ... users cannot opt out.</li>
  <li>The software is licensed. You may not work around limitations in the software, attempt to derive the source code,
    reverse engineer [...](etc., etc., etc.,) share, publish, or lend the software....</li>
  <li>Limitation on[...]damages. You can recover ... only up to $5.00 for lost profits or damages.</li>
</ul>

<p>...and to obtain the source you have a to send a check to Microsoft... and you access to the open-source third party
  libraries included in VS Code.</p>
<p>So tell me again how Microsoft is getting better, improving their open source activity, and all that bullshit? They
  built you an editor that will _stop running_ when they're ready to release it for real money. It will just stop
  working, and no longer access its own files. And they can press charges if you try to fix that. Literally, if you want
to hack on the source, you can't, because you signed an agreement saying you'd give them your firstborn and your right
kidney if you try to do so.</p>
<p>If you use VS Code and think you're using a decent editor you can continue to use for years to come, you're being
  duped. Sorry, that's all there is to it. Microsoft has never given a shit about users or developers, which is why they
gave us that lovely VBScript. Remember that? Yeah. Don't be so quick to jump on their bandwagon. It's bullshit.</p>

<p>tags: <a href='tag_microsoft.html'>microsoft</a>, <a href='tag_editor.html'>editor</a>, <a href='tag_vs-code.html'>vs-code</a>, <a href='tag_lol.html'>lol</a></p>








<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/visual-studio-codes-license.html&text=&lt;say nice things about me&gt;&via=zacanger'>so, tweet it?</a> 
<a href='http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http://zacanger.com/blog/visual-studio-codes-license.html'><span id='count-21178'></span></a>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><link>http://zacanger.com/blog/visual-studio-codes-license.html</link>
<guid>http://zacanger.com/blog/./visual-studio-codes-license.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Zac Anger</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 13:58:27 -0600</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
